<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Publications | Ilan Reinstein</title><link>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/</link><atom:link href="https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><description>Publications</description><generator>Wowchemy (https://wowchemy.com)</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><image><url>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/media/icon_hub1d11bc70e03781f784a7270814f1676_20092_512x512_fill_lanczos_center_3.png</url><title>Publications</title><link>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/</link></image><item><title>Learning Curves and Multilevel Models</title><link>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/learning-curves-multilevel-models/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/learning-curves-multilevel-models/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is one of the projects I am most proud of. It was a tremendously hard journey, with lots of obstacles, both technical and conceptual, which lead to a constant reformulation of our initial problem. Despite all the difficulties, we managed to build a relatively simple model which is to be tested on further studies and prototypes about learning curves. This is the project that got me started with Hierarchical Models and Bayesian Statistics. Even though we did not develop a full Bayesian model for this occasion, I was constantly learning new things about regression and multilevel models, which naturally takes you into the Bayesian world.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I had the privilege to collaborate with experts in the field like Martin Pusic, Jennifer Hill, David Cook, and Matthew Lineberry, among others.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>If you are interested in education, adaptive learning algorithms and the potential applications of multilevel models in this type of setting, then I&amp;rsquo;m sure this paper will be quite enjoyable.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Please do not hesitate to reach out with an questions you may have about this, I&amp;rsquo;ll be happy to discuss more.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>NYU's COVID-19 Response</title><link>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/nyu-covid-19-response/</link><pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://ilanreinstein.github.io/publication/nyu-covid-19-response/</guid><description>&lt;p>As one of many of NYU Langone&amp;rsquo;s data scientists, I got to collaborate with the wonderful team from the Predictive Analytics Unit from NYU&amp;rsquo;s Medical Center to develop a model capable of predicting which patients will have favorable outcomes after being hospitalized. These were intense weeks not only at NYU and I am proud of being able to contribute to this project and help our physicians during these challenging times.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>